by Henry David Thoreau

$8.49

Format: Paperback
Language: English
ISBN: 0486284956
ISBN13: 9780486284958
Release Date: April 1995
Publisher: Dover Publications

Overview
In the spring of 1845, Henry David Thoreau built a wooden hut on the shores of Walden Pond outside Concord, Massachusetts, intending to devote himself, for a time, to a simple life. The product of his two-year stay there was this volume of classic essays, one of the great books of American letters and a masterpiece of reflective philosophizing. Accounts of his daily life are interwoven with musings on the virtues of self-reliance and individual freedom, on society, government, and other topics--all expressed with clear-headed wisdom and remarkable beauty of style. Author: Henry David ThoreauFormat: 224 pages, paperbackPublisher: Dover ISBN: 0-486-28495-6