by Lois Lowry

$20.98

Format: Hardcover
Language: English
ISBN: 0618404414
ISBN13: 9780618404414
Release Date: April 2004
Publisher: HMH Books for Young Readers

Overview
Strange changes are taking place in Village. Once a utopian community that prided itself on its welcome to new strangers, Village will soon be closed to all outsiders. As one of the few people able to travel through the dangerous Forest, Matty must deliver the message of Village’s closing and try to convince Seer’s daughter to return with him before it’s too late. But Forest has become hostile to Matty as well, and he must risk everything to fight his way through it, armed only with an emerging power he cannot yet explain or understand.
(Book #3 in the The Giver Quartet series)