by J.K. Rowling

$100.00

Format: Paperback
Language: English
ISBN: 0545596270
ISBN13: 9780545596275
Release Date: August 2013
Publisher: Scholastic Inc.

Overview
The perfect gift for collectors and new readers alike, we now present a breathtaking special edition boxed set of J. K. Rowling's seven bestselling Harry Potter books! The box itself is beautifully designed with new artwork by Kazu Kibuishi, and the books create a gorgeous, magical vista when the spines are lined up together. The Harry Potter series has been hailed as "one for the ages" by Stephen King and "a spellbinding saga" by USA Today. Now is your chance to give this set to a reader who is ready to embark on the series that has changed so many young readers' lives.
(Complete Harry Potter Boxed Set)