by Andrea J. Buchanan and Miriam Peskowitz

$16.99

Format: Hardcover
Language: English
ISBN: 0062208969
ISBN13: 9780062208965
Release Date: March 2012
Publisher: William Morrow

Overview
The Daring Book for Girls is the manual for everything that girls need to know—and that doesn't mean sewing buttonholes! Whether it's female heroes in history, secret note-passing skills, science projects, friendship bracelets, double dutch, cats cradle, the perfect cartwheel or the eternal mystery of what boys are thinking, this book has it all. But it's not just a guide to giggling at sleepovers—although that's included, of course! Whether readers consider themselves tomboys, girly-girls, or a little bit of both, this book is every girl's invitation to adventure.
(Part of the Daring Books for Girls series)