by Elaine Mazlish and Adele Faber

$16.49

Format: Paperback
Language: English
ISBN: 0380570009
ISBN13: 9780380570003
Release Date: August 1991
Publisher: Avon Books (P)

Overview
How to Talk So Kids Will Listen and Listen So Kids Will Talk is an excellent communication tool kit based on a series of workshops developed by Adele Faber and Elaine Mazlish. Faber and Mazlish (coauthors of Siblings Without Rivalry) provide a step-by-step approach to improving relationships in your house. The "Reminder" pages, helpful cartoon illustrations, and excellent exercises will improve your ability as a parent to talk and problem-solve with your children. The book can be used alone or in parenting groups, and the solid tools provided are appropriate for kids of all ages.