by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry and Gregory Norminton

$8.94

Format: Paperback
Language: English
ISBN: 0156528207
ISBN13: 9780156528207
Release Date: January 1968
Publisher: Harcourt Childrens Books

Overview
A lovely story....which covers a poetic, yearning philosophy--not the sort of fable that can be tacked down neatly at its four corners but rather reflections on what are real matters of consequence. --The New York Times Book Review.